<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Salt Lake City Real Estate Podcast with Justin Udy</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Justin Udy & Team Real Estate - your professional Salt Lake City Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Justin Udy</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2019-02-15 14:28:48 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Justin Udy</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Salt Lake City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Justin@JustinUdy.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Justin Udy</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Justin Udy</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Salt Lake City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Salt Lake City Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Justin Udy & Team Real Estate - your professional Salt Lake City Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Protect Yourself From the Winter Inversion</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/protect-yourself-from-the-winter-inversion.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Justin Udy</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-24 12:07:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2019/January/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+Protect+Yourself+From+the+Winter+Inversion.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re feeling the effects of the winter inversion in our area, I have a few tips to share with you that will help you feel better and keep your family safe.

First, let’s recap what the winter inversion is. You see, air quality is often best in the wintertime when the weather works to clean the air, trapping ozone and other pollutants in precipitation or blowing them off with sharp, gusty winds. As the inversion goes on, this trapped air begins to stagnate, and the concentration of fine particle pollutants in the air, emitted by the consumption of fossil fuels in vehicles, power plants, and factories, increases. An extended period of inversion sometimes results in the formation of a brownish fog.

The first thing you can do to minimize the effects of the winter inversion is visit www.air.utah.gov to check the air quality in your area on any given day. 

“If you can physically feel the air affecting you in your day-to-day life, invest in an air purifier for your household.”

Second, if you’re like me and you prefer to exercise outside, try doing it during hours with low traffic activity. You can also exercise in high-altitude areas above the fog.

There are several tips you can try that will also help the environment at large, including:


  Not burning trash 
  Recycling
  Carpooling
  Turning off your car when you’re waiting to pick up your kids from school


Lastly, if you can physically feel the air affecting you in your day-to-day life, invest in an air purifier for your household. My family did this, and although it was expensive, it’s made a big difference for us.

If you have any more questions about this topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2019/January/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+Protect+Yourself+From+the+Winter+Inversion.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2019/January/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+Protect+Yourself+From+the+Winter+Inversion.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our area suffers from a winter inversion, but there are a few tips you can follow to protect yourself from it.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Justin Udy</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our area suffers from a winter inversion, but there are a few tips you can follow to protect yourself from it.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Salt Lake City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Accomplish Your 2019 Goals</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-accomplish-your-2019-goals.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Justin Udy</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-08 12:14:34 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/December/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Accomplish+Your+2019+Goals.mp4</guid>
        <description>

2018 is quickly coming to an end, and next year will be here before we know it. We want to wish you a happy new year, and we hope midnight on the 31st kicks off a great 2019 for you and your loved ones. Now’s the time where people start to think about what they want to change in their lives throughout the coming year, and I’d like to help everyone do so.

One of my favorite recently discovered quotes comes from G.K. Chesterton, who said, “When it comes to life, the critical thing is whether you take things for granted or take them with gratitude.”

“We can put ourselves in a place where we can bless the lives of others.”

We’re so fortunate to be where we are, but we also need to have goals so we can put ourselves in a place where we can bless the lives of others. To do this, we need to improve. Here are a few things that have worked for me when it comes to self-improvement:


  I write down my goals. Along with my children, I come up with things I want to accomplish in the future. After some decoration, we put up our lists and are able to keep track of our progress throughout the year.
  I make SMART goals. This acronym is about how to structure your goals and stands for specific, measurable, achievable, relevant, and time-bound. Following these criteria will ensure that you reach the goals you wish to accomplish.


I would also like to share Tony Robbins’ rapid planning method with you.


  What is the item that you’re looking for?
  What is the purpose?
  What are the actions you can take today?


I hope some of these methods can help you accomplish your own goals in 2019. If you have any questions or real estate needs I can help you with, reach out to me. Until then, have a great new year! I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/December/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Accomplish+Your+2019+Goals.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/December/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Accomplish+Your+2019+Goals.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Make 2019 your best year yet by setting and reaching your goals.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Justin Udy</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Make 2019 your best year yet by setting and reaching your goals.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Salt Lake City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is Our Market Undergoing a Shift?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/is-our-market-undergoing-a-shift.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Justin Udy</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-08 12:10:50 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/December/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+Is+Our+Market+Undergoing+a+Shift%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

For the past several years, we’ve seen our real estate market go up and up and up, but lately, things have cooled off a bit.  Prices are softening—not as many buyers are inquiring about our listings, and we’re not seeing as many showings happening.

The good news is that this is nothing to worry about. The housing market goes in cycles that typically last seven to 10 years. When interest rates rise and prices go up, these factors essentially make the housing market adjust.

“Unlike other parts of the country, our job rate isn’t going down, and we still have a lot of people moving here.”

In our case, it’s not a housing availability issue—it’s an affordability issue. Home prices and interest rates have risen so quickly that it’s made homes unaffordable for many people. We’ve also heard new construction builders say they won’t be building as many homes above $500,000.

Our local economy, however, is still doing fantastic. Unlike other parts of the country, our job rate isn’t going down, and we still have a lot of people moving here. This shift is nothing to be scared of, but it’s still something to keep in mind moving forward.

If you have any more questions about our Salt Lake City market or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/December/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+Is+Our+Market+Undergoing+a+Shift%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/December/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+Is+Our+Market+Undergoing+a+Shift%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our market is undergoing a bit of a shift, but this is normal and nothing to be alarmed about.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Justin Udy</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our market is undergoing a bit of a shift, but this is normal and nothing to be alarmed about.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Salt Lake City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Things to Consider When Buying an Investment Property</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-things-to-consider-when-buying-an-investment-property.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Justin Udy</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-08 12:07:44 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/November/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+Things+to+Consider+When+Buying+an+Investment+Property.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How do we know when a property is a good investment deal? There are four major things we need to look at to before we decide to buy:

1. Pricing. Is the property price in line with the market, as well as features of the home? We need to pull values and look at criteria, such as curb appeal, bathrooms, and amenities. We want the price to make sense with what we’re getting.

2. Features and benefits. You need to decide if it’s worth paying potentially tens of thousands more for a good view or a pool. Is there an exit strategy for us if we need out? These are things to keep in mind.

“We want the price to make sense with what we’re getting.”

3. Location. Sometimes the best deals aren’t actually places we ourselves would want to live. We have to think of it from the perspective of, “Could I see myself living here? Would I want to stay here for years? Would I be happy here long term?”

4. Condition. You may love a property, but it could become a money pit if it’s in bad condition. We purchased an investment property and had to renovate it for $250,000. With properties such as this, it doesn’t matter what the details, location, and benefits are—a place in bad condition needs a long, hard look.

If you have any questions, need information, or have video topics you’d like covered in the future, we’d love to help you out. Please call, email, or message us; we look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/November/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+Things+to+Consider+When+Buying+an+Investment+Property.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/November/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+4+Things+to+Consider+When+Buying+an+Investment+Property.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Considering investing in property? Here are four things to keep in mind.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Justin Udy</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Considering investing in property? Here are four things to keep in mind.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Salt Lake City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Take Advantage of Fall and Sell Now</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/take-advantage-of-fall-and-sell-now.html</link>
        
          <category>Salt Lake City Real Estate Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Justin Udy</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-22 11:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/October/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+Take+Advantage+of+Fall+and+Sell+Now.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are five primary reasons why fall presents a great opportunity to sell your home quickly and for top dollar.


Selling your Salt Lake City home? Get a free home value report
Buying a Salt Lake City home? Search all homes for sale


Here are the top five reasons the fall is actually a great time to sell your home.

First, there’s less competition on the market. During this time, a lot of other home sellers end up taking their homes off the market because their kids are busy with school, they have work obligations, or selling at the end of the year just doesn’t make sense for them.

Second, buyers are more motivated to buy. They want to get into a home before the holidays arrive or before the end of the year. It’s possible that some have been searching since the summer, and they’re ready to become homeowners now.

“DURING THIS TIME, A LOT OF OTHER HOME SELLERS END UP TAKING THEIR HOMES OFF THE MARKET.”

Third, interest rates are still phenomenal. Interest rates have adjusted, and sometimes when that happens, affordability becomes an issue. If you sell now, though, you can still lock a buyer into a low rate.

Fourth, homes show beautifully during the fall. 92% of all buyers start their home search online, and 64% will pay more for a home that looks move-in ready. This is why a lot of folks who plan on putting their home on the market in December or January are taking photos of it now.

Lastly, it’s a lot easier to move now than when there’s snow on the ground.

If you’d like to put your home on the market now or you have any questions about our market, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/October/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+Take+Advantage+of+Fall+and+Sell+Now.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/October/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+Take+Advantage+of+Fall+and+Sell+Now.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

There are five primary reasons why fall presents a great opportunity to sell your home quickly and for top dollar.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Justin Udy</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

There are five primary reasons why fall presents a great opportunity to sell your home quickly and for top dollar.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Salt Lake City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Discussion for Sellers & Investors</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-discussion-for-sellers-investors.html</link>
        
          <category>Salt Lake City Real Estate Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Salt Lake City Real Estate Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Justin Udy</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-08 15:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/October/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Discussion+for+Sellers+%2526+Investors.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are you thinking of selling your home or investing in real estate? My recent Facebook Live interview discusses both of these topics in depth.


Selling your Salt Lake City home? Get a free home value report
Buying a Salt Lake City home? Search all homes for sale


I recently sat down for a Facebook Live interview where I discussed how to maximize your home’s value before putting it on the market and the key concepts you need to know if you’re thinking about investing in real estate.

For your convenience, I’ve attached the timestamps of this interview so you can jump ahead to the section(s) that interest you the most:

0:12 - The four areas you need to focus on to maximize your property’s value when listing it.
0:55 - How we can assist sellers in improving your property’s curb appeal.
2:04 - How to get over the fear of getting into investing.

“DON’T WAIT TO BUY REAL ESTATE—BUY REAL ESTATE AND WAIT.”

5:19 - The factors I take into consideration when I look at an investment property.
8:19 - One of the biggest problems people face with investment properties.
8:53 - How I can help you get started with buying an investment property.
9:52 - The advantages of buying an investment property right now.

If you have any questions about any of the topics I discussed in this interview, don’t hesitate to call or email me anytime. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/October/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Discussion+for+Sellers+%2526+Investors.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/October/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Discussion+for+Sellers+%2526+Investors.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Are you thinking of selling your home or investing in real estate? My recent Facebook Live interview discusses both of these topics in depth.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Justin Udy</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Are you thinking of selling your home or investing in real estate? My recent Facebook Live interview discusses both of these topics in depth.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Salt Lake City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What You Need to Know About the Utah Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-you-need-to-know-about-utah-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Justin Udy</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-27 10:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

What is happening in our Utah Market? Today I am going to look at it with you.


Selling your Salt Lake City home? Get a free home value report
Buying a Salt Lake City home? Search all homes for sale


Today I want to give you a quick market update and tell you what you need to know about real estate in Utah.

When comparing this quarter to last quarter, we are down 4.6% in home sales. In fact, the Board of Realtors said that, if we looked at listings, they are down 1.6%.

While we are seeing less homes on the market, our home values have increased dramatically. Since last year, the median home price in Salt Lake County has increased 7.8% from $327,000 to $352,000.

Of course, different markets and areas are seeing different trends. However, this market has been fantastic with 10 years of growth.

Now, though, interest rates are increasing which affects affordability. Recently, we had a buyer looking for a $440,000 home, but interest rates increased and reduced his affordability to $410,000. If you are selling a home, this changes the number of people that can buy your home.

When we have less homes on the market, people become afraid of where they are going to go and buyers think that they can’t afford a home. Statistically, property values have increased by an average of 3.3%over the last 26 years.

What you need to know is this: Interest rates are still great, but they are going up. It is affecting the affordability and is starting to squeeze the value and the affordability of homes.

You are going to start seeing more and more townhome projects that come to your city planning meetings as well as smaller micro units. Also, according to economists at the University of Utah, we are seeing an increase in the number of multi-generational families that are living in the same habitation due to affordability concerns.

If you need anything such as a home value or a new home, now is a great time to look at different options. For sellers, it’s a good time to decide whether to sell or keep your home. Meanwhile, if you are looking at buying, you can look at the interest rates to see if it’s a good time to buy. I will say this: Never wait to buy real estate.

If you have any questions, please feel free to contact me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

What is happening in our Utah Market? Today I am going to look at it with you.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Justin Udy</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

What is happening in our Utah Market? Today I am going to look at it with you.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Salt Lake City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Things You Can Do to Stage Your Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-things-you-can-do-to-stage-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Salt Lake City Real Estate Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Justin Udy</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-21 12:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/August/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Things+You+Can+Do+to+Stage+Your+Home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I am sharing five decorating and staging tips to help maximize the value of your home.


Selling your Salt Lake City home? Get a free home value report
Buying a Salt Lake City home? Search all homes for sale


Did you know that 63% of buyers will actually pay more for a move-in ready home? Decorating and staging your home can improve its look and feel. To help you maximize the value of your property, I am going to share five home decorating and staging tips for you to think about.

1. Make repairs to the home. There are always a couple of repairs that need to be made. I love to say “pick five.” Sometimes there’s a baseboard missing, a light is missing, or a window is cracked. Find five things that need to be fixed, because fixing them will make your home look well-maintained.

2. Make sure your home is white-glove clean. Your property should be spotless, both inside and out, and free of odors, as well.

3. Look at the colors in your home. People love neutral colors. Paint over the large red wall that was once a great look with a neutral color. It is going to make it feel bright and will help modernize your home. Fresh coats of paint can also help your home smell like it’s brand new.

“YOU NEED TO MAKE SURE THAT YOUR PROPERTY IS SPOTLESS BOTH INSIDE AND OUT AS WELL AS ELIMINATE ALL ODORS.”

4. Declutter your home. After we have already done some work and added color, you need to declutter. You either want to toss it, give it, or prioritize it. If there are things that you haven’t touched in the last two years, you probably aren’t going to use them again and can instead get rid of them.

Less is more, and the more belongings you have, the more cluttered your home will feel. When you do stage your home, think about the buyer. If your home is in an area where 90% of the buyers are going to have kids and potentially a baby, consider putting a cradle in a room. If it is going to be a business executive that might buy the home, make a room an office.

5. Depersonalize the home. Get rid of the religious photos and the collections. I also think that you should get rid of the personal photographs. The reason that this is important is that while you may worship Dale Earnhardt, not everybody does. You want to make it so that every consumer that goes in there can see what the home is and not what you love.

If you have any additional questions about staging or would like a full list of staging recommendations, please feel free to contact us and we can get that to you. And, as always, if you are looking to buy or sell, reach out to us by phone or email. We would be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/August/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Things+You+Can+Do+to+Stage+Your+Home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/August/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Things+You+Can+Do+to+Stage+Your+Home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I am sharing five decorating and staging tips to help maximize the value of your home.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Justin Udy</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I am sharing five decorating and staging tips to help maximize the value of your home.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Salt Lake City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Roadblocks on the Path to Your New Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-roadblocks-on-path-to-your-new-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Salt Lake City Real Estate Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Justin Udy</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-26 15:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/June/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Questions+That+Will+Determine+Which+Home+Upgrades+to+Make.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When you are purchasing a home, you want to have the smoothest transaction possible. There are five roadblocks that can prevent that smooth transaction from happening.


Selling your Salt Lake City home? Get a free home value report
Buying a Salt Lake City home? Search all homes for sale


Whenever you purchase a home, there are five major things that can happen that can stop our sales. Today I am going to share those five roadblocks, so you can know what to avoid if you are buying a new home.

1. Damage. Damages can occur when the seller moves out, or from a contractor who has caused additional damage. To remedy this, you must always do a walk-through inspection. This can help you avoid discovering that things are missing, such as light bulbs, fixtures, or—even worse—appliances and cabinetry.

2. Due diligence.  During the home inspection, ensure that all the repairs requested by the inspection are completed. Also, make sure that your insurance is active the day that you close—accidents happen, and you do not want to accidentally cause a fire. If your insurance is not set up at closing, it could cause a delay.

3. Survey. Survey the land to find out where proper property lines are. This is something a lot of agents push to the side, but do not let them. Surveys are very important.

I personally purchased a duplex as an investment property and noticed something was strange about the lines. I had a survey completed and found that the neighbor had encroached 15 feet into the property that I was purchasing. I ended up giving him notice and putting up a fence. Now I have an entire parking spot for my tenant.

“I COMPLETED A SURVEY OF A PROPERTY THAT I HAD PURCHASED, ONLY TO DISCOVER THAT THE NEIGHBOR HAD ENCROACHED NEARLY 15 FEET INTO MY NEW PROPERTY.”

4. Major purchases. Refrain from big dollar purchases. Buying a car will affect your credit score, which may affect your mortgage rate and eventually affect your ability to even purchase the home.

5. Loan approval. If a person unknowingly does something to impact their credit, they may be unable to secure a loan. Leaving a job or making an expensive purchase are just two of the ways someone may accidentally damage their score

A loan company verifies your employment the day before closing. If you quit or lose your job the day before, you may end up unqualified for the loan because of lack of income.

Having the money in the location it needs to be is also crucial. If you are receiving the money as a gift, it needs to be wired to your account before closing to verify that you have the sufficient funds. Very few people will let you have the keys to your new place if they are waiting for money to be approved for one reason or another—make sure that the funds are ready.

If you have any questions about this or are interested in buying or selling, please feel free to contact me. I look forward to speaking to you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/June/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Questions+That+Will+Determine+Which+Home+Upgrades+to+Make.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/June/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Questions+That+Will+Determine+Which+Home+Upgrades+to+Make.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

When you are purchasing a home, you want to have the smoothest transaction possible. There are five roadblocks that can prevent that smooth transaction from happening.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Justin Udy</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

When you are purchasing a home, you want to have the smoothest transaction possible. There are five roadblocks that can prevent that smooth transaction from happening.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Salt Lake City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Questions That Will Determine Which Home Upgrades to Make</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-questions-that-will-determine-which.html</link>
        
          <category>Salt Lake City Real Estate Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Justin Udy</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-21 14:29:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/June/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Questions+That+Will+Determine+Which+Home+Upgrades+to+Make.mp4</guid>
        <description>

To know which upgrades you should make to your home, there are five questions you need to ask yourself.


Selling your Salt Lake City home? Get a free home value report
Buying a Salt Lake City home? Search all homes for sale


Here are the five questions you need to ask yourself to know which home upgrades will give you the biggest bang for your buck:

1. Does it make sense? Does it make sense for you to invest money into your property? If your home is in an area you don’t want to live in anymore and you’re ready to move, it probably doesn’t make sense to invest any money into it other than what can be put toward getting it ready for sale.

2. Does it make sense economically? Do you have the cash on-hand to put into your property in order for the renovation to be a successful investment? Sometimes in this situation, homeowners take out a home equity line of credit at a typically low interest rate. If you do something like this, the goal is to pay off debt immediately. I don’t love second mortgages, so my advice is to not use one unless you don’t have the cash on-hand, you know you’ll be in the house long-term, and you know you’ll see a return on your investment.

“ASKING THESE QUESTIONS CAN HELP YOU BUILD WEALTH THROUGH REAL ESTATE.”

3. Will you see a return on your investment (ROI)? To know if a renovation makes sense, you need to understand the market you’re in and the type of property you have. Do you really need marble floors installed into your $300,000 home or would hardwood or laminate floors make more sense?

4. Will your upgrade(s) be sellable? Sometimes we want to make an amazing upgrade, but it just doesn’t make sense to do so. I’ve seen people make adjustments to their home where their space was so unique that it made it difficult for anyone else to move into that space

5. Will your upgrade(s) make sense long-term? Anytime you put money into a property, it has to make sense in terms of the general market. You might want to take out three bedrooms and two bathrooms on your main level and turn them into one master bedroom and one master bathroom, but your neighborhood might not be conducive to those upgrades. That neighborhood, for instance, might be in a price point more appropriate for first-time homebuyers or those looking for a move-up property. You don’t want to make upgrades to your home that will hurt its value.

One of the goals I want to help you with is to build wealth through real estate, and asking these kinds of questions can accomplish this goal.

If you have any questions about this or any other real estate topic or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/June/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Questions+That+Will+Determine+Which+Home+Upgrades+to+Make.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/June/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Questions+That+Will+Determine+Which+Home+Upgrades+to+Make.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

To know which upgrades you should make to your home, there are five questions you need to ask yourself.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Justin Udy</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

To know which upgrades you should make to your home, there are five questions you need to ask yourself.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Salt Lake City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Affordability Is Affected by Increased Prices</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-affordability-is-affected-by.html</link>
        
          <category>Salt Lake City Real Estate Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Justin Udy</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-05 12:07:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/June/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Affordability+is+Affected+by+Increased+Prices.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What do our current increased prices mean to you? If you are an owner, it means that you have more money without even doing anything.


Selling your Salt Lake City home? Get a free home value report
Buying a Salt Lake City home? Search all homes for sale


Today I want to talk to you about how the increase in pricing, interest rates, and affordability can affect you and your home.

Many people have been asking about what the market is going to do and where are we going. Here are the facts. The market is growing. The prices are rising. And, interest rates are going up.

These factors create an issue where someone that could previously afford a home for $1500/mo. is now looking at paying $1,700 to $1,800 per month. This is not just because the rates went up but also because the value of the home increased. People are running into the issue of how it affects them and their homes.

Compared to last year, we are finding a couple of differences. One is that we have even fewer homes on the market, but we have more sales occurring in the market. This creates a supply and demand issue which pushes up prices.

“INCREASED PRICES AFFECT YOUR HOME PERSONALLY BECAUSE YOUR HOME IS NOW GROWING IN EQUITY.”

This affects your home personally because your home is now growing in equity.

With that new equity, you can take it and sell your home, and buy a larger home. Also, if you are planning on upsizing, you have the amount you have paid off for your current mortgage which you can transfer to a new property.

Or, you can use that new equity to get a home equity line of credit for updates. If you have the cash, I do suggest you use it. However, using this will allow you to make your home a better place for you and your family.

Finally, you can keep the equity where it is and continue to own this same property. You can either continue to live there yourself, or you could also turn it into an investment property.

If you can make it an investment property with a higher lease than your mortgage payment, this will create an amazing source of income. It also creates a part of a portfolio for future growth.

So, just consider that when there are changes in the market and issues with affordability, it unfortunately creates a situation where some people who want to buy are pushed out of the market. They instead continue to rent. While the real estate market does go up and down over time, rents will continue to increase.

Hopefully you can consider this as an opportunity to get in our growing market. In the event that it does slow, you wouldn’t have an issue like you would with renting because you will already be locked in with a great rate.

If you have any further questions or would like to speak to me about buying or selling, please feel free to contact me by phone or email. I look forward to speaking with you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/June/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Affordability+is+Affected+by+Increased+Prices.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/June/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Affordability+is+Affected+by+Increased+Prices.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

What do our current increased prices mean to you? If you are an owner, it means that you have more money without even doing anything.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Justin Udy</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

What do our current increased prices mean to you? If you are an owner, it means that you have more money without even doing anything.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Salt Lake City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Prepare for Your Next Real Estate Investment</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-prepare-for-your-next-real.html</link>
        
          <category>Salt Lake City Real Estate Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Justin Udy</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-16 13:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/May/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Prepare+for+Your+Next+Real+Estate+Investment.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re thinking about investing in real estate in order to build wealth, you’re not alone. Here are some tips that will get you started off on the right foot.


Selling your Salt Lake City home? Get a free home value report
Buying a Salt Lake City home? Search all homes for sale


What does it take to buy a home? If you are someone who is looking to buy a new home or helping someone else through the process, there are some things that you should know. Today I have a quick list of things that you need to know:

Before I was ever a real estate agent, I was buying and selling investment properties. This is something I’ve always enjoyed and something you should think about. Whether you’re thinking about buying your first property or your fifth, here are a few helpful tips for success with investment properties:

1. Always make sure your finances are in order. We are finding fantastic properties, but when one buyer’s finances fall through there are always three or four back-up offers from eager buyers waiting to pounce. The seller won’t hesitate to move to the next in line if you’re not prepared.

2. Be proactive about having everyone and everything ready to go. If we’re dealing with a development, that means we need engineers, geotech, soil testing, surveyors, and architects. We want to make sure that we have the proper forms, rent rates, and every other detail ready to go. We have all of these resources ready for you so that you can find success.

“INVESTING IN REAL ESTATE IS A FANTASTIC WAY TO BUILD WEALTH.”

3. Find the project. The market is great and I think it will go up for at least the next 18 months. There’s going to be an affordability issue at some point, and then you’ll see a leveling off.

When it comes to what investors should be looking for in a property, there are three must-haves:


  
    The property must have equity already.
  
  
    There is an opportunity to maximize its best use.
  
  
    There is a potential for cash flow.
  


If you don’t have these three things, you’re facing an uphill battle. For example, if you don’t have a property that’s cash-flow positive, that’s when people go bankrupt and lose everything. Back during the mortgage crisis, my rentals went down significantly in value, but the rents remained the same. I was able to use that money to sustain my business during those tough times.

There are so many opportunities involved with investing in real estate. If you have any questions or you want to learn more, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/May/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Prepare+for+Your+Next+Real+Estate+Investment.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/May/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Prepare+for+Your+Next+Real+Estate+Investment.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you’re thinking about investing in real estate in order to build wealth, you’re not alone. Here are some tips that will get you started off on the right foot.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Justin Udy</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’re thinking about investing in real estate in order to build wealth, you’re not alone. Here are some tips that will get you started off on the right foot.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Salt Lake City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Steps in the Home Buying Process</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-steps-in-home-buying-process.html</link>
        
          <category>Salt Lake City Real Estate Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Justin Udy</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-04 11:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/May/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Steps+in+the+Home+Buying+Process.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Do you know what it takes to buy a home? Today I have five tips to share about the home buying process.


Selling your Salt Lake City home? Get a free home value report
Buying a Salt Lake City home? Search all homes for sale


What does it take to buy a home? If you are someone who is looking to buy a new home or helping someone else through the process, there are some things that you should know. Today I have a quick list of things that you need to know:

1. You have got to talk to somebody that is an expert advisor. You need someone that can help you navigate through the process. They must know what to look for—not only the problems of the sticks and bricks, but of the values of that property short term and long term. Get the right person—somebody that understands the market and can take you through everything.

2. Shop for the perfect property. It may be easy to look online, but it’s hard to narrow down your options. Sometimes it involves taking your 100 favorite properties and narrowing it down to your top ten before picking out one. At the end of the day, set a parameter. Then we can help you look for a home and make an offer. We evaluate not only the values of the market but also what we’re seeing today.

“SET A PARAMETER, THEN WE CAN HELP YOU LOOK FOR A HOME.”

3. You will want to research it. You have to know, based on the offer and what has been established, is that property worth it? We bring in all of our resources, including home inspectors, engineers, and electricians, with specialized expertise that can help us check it out and get more information about that property. Every property is completely different.

4. Make sure that you are keeping your finances safe. Don’t buy dumb things or lose/quit your job. Keep everything in order. Make sure that everything is perfect with finances.

5. Next, we are going through closing. We’ve set everything up. We have researched the property, found the perfect home, and our finances are ready. Once the appraisal is back and the due diligence is complete, we are going to close the property and get the keys. You own it.

If you have any questions about this process or want to know more about why you should buy now, please don’t hesitate to contact me. I would be happy to speak with you any time by phone or email. I look forward to speaking with you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/May/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Steps+in+the+Home+Buying+Process.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/May/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Steps+in+the+Home+Buying+Process.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Do you know what it takes to buy a home? Today I have five tips to share about the home buying process.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Justin Udy</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Do you know what it takes to buy a home? Today I have five tips to share about the home buying process.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Salt Lake City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Which Home Remodeling Projects Bring the Best Return?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/which-home-remodeling-projects-bring.html</link>
        
          <category>Salt Lake City Real Estate Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Justin Udy</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-20 12:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/March/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+Which+Home+Remodeling+Projects+Bring+the+Best+Return%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Which remodel projects will bring the highest returns when you list your home? Let’s take a look at the results of a recent study.


Selling your Salt Lake City home? Get a free home value report
Buying a Salt Lake City home? Search all homes for sale


Remodeling Magazine recently came out with a list of the top projects with the highest return on investment.

I’m going to share this list with you today but before I do, there’s something I want you to keep in mind: Things in our market might be a little different than what works well on a national level. Overall, this list has a lot of great points that can help you earn more money for your home.

Before you make any major remodels, we’d be happy to provide you with guidance as to which projects will work best for your home.

“BEFORE YOU MAKE ANY MAJOR REMODELS, PLEASE COME TO US FOR GUIDANCE.”

Finally, let’s take a look at the list of top projects:

  Attic insulation
  A new front door
  Stone veneer
  A new garage door
  Kitchen updates
  New siding
  New windows


If you would like to see the full list and a more detailed breakdown of the statistics supporting it, click here.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/March/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+Which+Home+Remodeling+Projects+Bring+the+Best+Return%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/March/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+Which+Home+Remodeling+Projects+Bring+the+Best+Return%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Which remodel projects will bring the highest returns when you list your home? Let’s take a look at the results of a recent study.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Justin Udy</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Which remodel projects will bring the highest returns when you list your home? Let’s take a look at the results of a recent study.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Salt Lake City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Can You Expect From a Home Inspection?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-can-you-expect-from-home-inspection.html</link>
        
          <category>Salt Lake City Real Estate Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Justin Udy</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-29 14:24:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/January/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Can+You+Expect+From+a+Home+Inspection%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, I’ll be going over what you should expect from the home inspection process.


Selling your Salt Lake City home? Get a free home value report
Buying a Salt Lake City home? Search all homes for sale


What should you expect during an inspection?

First of all, there are three general types of inspections: a surface inspection, an in-depth inspection, and a professional inspection.

A surface inspection is a basic walkthrough of the home. When this kind of inspection is performed, the inspector is looking for anything that might interfere with the property in terms of safety or stability. Things like burn marks, mold, or other physical identifiers of poor condition.

Surface inspections are only done about 10% of the time. Frankly, these kinds of inspections miss quite a few things, since they aren’t conducted by a professional home inspector.

“A HOME INSPECTOR IS GOING TO FIND SOMETHING WRONG, EVEN IF THE HOME IS A NEW CONSTRUCTION.”

This is why we recommend an in-depth inspection. A home inspector is going to find something wrong even if the home is a new construction. Inspectors, like attorneys, will always find an issue. They have been hired to do so.

When buyers and sellers negotiate the issues found in an in-depth home inspection, they will pay the most attention to safety and maintenance issues. It will depend on the individual transaction as to what fixes the buyer asks the seller to make or whether they ask them to make any repairs at all.

If the issues that are significant or specific enough, it may be time to hire a specialized professional to take a look. Using the example of a home with electrical problems, you may want to have an additional inspection performed by an electrician.

Any repairs that need to be made will typically be done within the due diligence period before closing.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/January/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Can+You+Expect+From+a+Home+Inspection%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/January/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Can+You+Expect+From+a+Home+Inspection%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today, I’ll be going over what you should expect from the home inspection process.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Justin Udy</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today, I’ll be going over what you should expect from the home inspection process.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Salt Lake City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Whats Causing Buyers to Be So Optimistic Right Now?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whats-causing-buyers-to-be-so.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Justin Udy</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-15 10:38:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/January/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+Causing+Buyers+to+Be+So+Optimistic+Right+Now%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

A lot of buyers now are more prone to buying a home than previously. I have a few thoughts about why that is.


Selling your Salt Lake City home? Get a free home value report
Buying a Salt Lake City home? Search all homes for sale


Why is buyer optimism higher than we’ve ever seen it? Today, I’d like to go over a couple reasons for this mindset.

Fannie Mae recently did a study that demonstrated that a large number of buyers were more prone to and optimistic about buying a home. If you think about inventory from a national level, you’ll get some interesting numbers. We are about 6.5% lower in inventory compared to last year, and yet, we’re about 6.9% higher in appreciation, price, and growth.

“TYPICALLY, THE SUCCESS OF THE MARKET IS TYPICALLY TIED TO ECONOMIC FACTORS AND GROWTH—TWO AREAS IN WHICH WE ARE DOING FANTASTIC.”

So with that in mind, what is giving buyers the sense of optimism we’ve seen?

1. Interest rates have remained pretty low over the year. Even though prices are rising, interest rates have gone down and have actually made it more affordable to purchase, despite that change.

2. The demographic of who’s on the market has shifted. When Fannie Mae did the study, they found that the average homeowner’s income was around 125% of someone who was buying. Right now, it’s actually closer to 150%. Millennials who were previously holding off on entering the market are now beginning to look at purchasing homes, as opposed to renting.

3. There has been steady job growth. Because of this growth, the market is starting to look appealing to more people.

If you’re a buyer, know that our market is good, interest rates are fantastic, and inventory is excellent. If you’re a seller, just know that there is a market of people looking to purchase. We expect to see a great market over the next few years as well. The world of real estate can always change, but typically, the success of the market is typically tied to economic factors and growth—two areas in which we are doing fantastic.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/January/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+Causing+Buyers+to+Be+So+Optimistic+Right+Now%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2018/January/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+Causing+Buyers+to+Be+So+Optimistic+Right+Now%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

A lot of buyers now are more prone to buying a home than previously. I have a few thoughts about why that is.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Justin Udy</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

A lot of buyers now are more prone to buying a home than previously. I have a few thoughts about why that is.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Salt Lake City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is the History of Our Market Bound to Repeat Itself?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/is-history-of-our-market-bound-to.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Justin Udy</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-02 12:35:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2017/January/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+Is+the+History+of+Our+Market+Bound+to+Repeat+Itself%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our market right now is seeing a lot of growth. But, does this growth point to potential issues on the horizon?


Selling your Salt Lake City home? Get a free home value report
Buying a Salt Lake City home? Search all homes for sale


Is history repeating itself?

Right now, some people are worried about the state of our market. People are afraid that the extensive, fast growth we’ve seen over time is going to lead to the market bottoming out.

I’ve witnessed some truly heartbreaking transactions in the past. I have even seen sellers weep at the closing table. But, is our market as scary as some think?

Well, I look at a large quantity of information pertaining to real estate each and every day. There are so many economic factors that drive our market, and all of these factors are ones I closely examine all the time.

“THE BOTTOM LINE IS THAT OUR CURRENT REAL ESTATE MARKET IS STILL GOING STRONG.”

It is these same factors, which can cause issues, that can also cause a great deal of growth and opportunity. So if you’re concerned about our market, you may want to consider a few factors. Our market is not the same as it has been in the past.

Current interest rates are phenomenal and lenders are being picky—they are making sure that buyers are truly responsible enough to move forward in a transaction.

Another factor that is different about today’s market is that we’re seeing much more dynamic job growth these days. People are coming to our city for our jobs, culture, and amenities. The bottom line is that our current real estate market is still going strong. We are definitely in a healthy market.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2017/January/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+Is+the+History+of+Our+Market+Bound+to+Repeat+Itself%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2017/January/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+Is+the+History+of+Our+Market+Bound+to+Repeat+Itself%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Our market right now is seeing a lot of growth. But, does this growth point to potential issues on the horizon?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Justin Udy</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Our market right now is seeing a lot of growth. But, does this growth point to potential issues on the horizon?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Salt Lake City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Can Terms Be More Important Than Price?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/can-terms-be-more-important-than-price.html</link>
        
          <category>Salt Lake City Real Estate Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Justin Udy</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-15 11:38:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2017/November/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+Can+Terms+Be+More+Important+Than+Price%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Why should you be paying attention to the terms of the market? Actually, there are a couple of reasons.


Selling your Salt Lake City home? Get a free home value report
Buying a Salt Lake City home? Search all homes for sale


Why should you be paying attention to the terms of the market? Actually, there are a couple of reasons.

Whether you’re buying an investment property, you’re buying a second property, or are moving into a single-family home, the terms of the market are just as valuable as the price.

Let’s take the example of comparing a $1 million home at a 1% interest rate to a $100,000 home with a 10% interest rate. These payments would end up being very similar, but the real issue is the terms of the interest rate.

“THE TERMS OF THE MARKET ARE JUST AS VALUABLE AS THE PRICE.”

There are a few quick statistics I’d like you to think about. The average rental rate in the market is constantly rising. And with all of the people currently moving into our area, this is expected to continue.

My point is that: interest rates in the market allow us to purchase and own at a better price. This means you can typically own a home for less money than it would take to rent one.

These interest rates will not last. And when they do rise, you won’t be able to match the kind of terms we’re seeing today.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2017/November/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+Can+Terms+Be+More+Important+Than+Price%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2017/November/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent-+Can+Terms+Be+More+Important+Than+Price%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Why should you be paying attention to the terms of the market? Actually, there are a couple of reasons.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Justin Udy</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Why should you be paying attention to the terms of the market? Actually, there are a couple of reasons.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Salt Lake City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Make Your Home Ready for Fall and Winter</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-make-your-home-ready-for-fall.html</link>
        
          <category>Salt Lake City Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        <author>Justin Udy</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-31 14:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2017/October/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent%3A+How+to+Make+Your+Home+Ready+for+Fall+and+Winter.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, I want to go over a few essential maintenance tips for the fall and winter months.


Selling your Salt Lake City home? Get a free home value report
Buying a Salt Lake City home? Search all homes for sale


Today I want to go over a few fall maintenance tips.

Fall and winter hit us very quickly here in Utah, so there are a few ways you should think about preparing before it’s too late in the year to do so.

First, get an automatic change form if you have renters in your property. That way, the property is automatically transferred to your name if they leave. I have literally walked into properties where I’ve found ice hanging from the ceilings. Getting an automatic change form can avoid disasters like this.

Secondly, make sure you seal everything. Water can cause mold and structural damage, so make sure your doors, windows, and other areas are all properly sealed.

“YOU ABSOLUTELY DO NOT WANT YOUR FURNACE TO GO OUT WHEN IT’S 10 DEGREES OUTSIDE.”

This brings me to my third tip, which is to seal your gutters. I’ve seen basements actually flood because of water coming down from the gutter and directly into the basement.

Also, another tip I want you to think about is to check your furnace on an annual basis. You absolutely do not want your furnace to go out when it’s 10 degrees outside. Make sure you are checking and maintaining it as needed.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2017/October/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent%3A+How+to+Make+Your+Home+Ready+for+Fall+and+Winter.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2017/October/Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent%3A+How+to+Make+Your+Home+Ready+for+Fall+and+Winter.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today, I want to go over a few essential maintenance tips for the fall and winter months.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Justin Udy</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today, I want to go over a few essential maintenance tips for the fall and winter months.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Salt Lake City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Dont Make These 3 Common Homebuyer Mistakes</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/dont-make-these-3-common-homebuyer.html</link>
        
          <category>Salt Lake City Real Estate Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Justin Udy</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-25 14:07:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2017/September/Dont+Make+These+3+Common+Homebuyer+Mistakes+-+Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

f you are using a loan to finance your home purchase, there are three mistakes you need to avoid if you want to close on the property.


Selling your Salt Lake City home? Get a free home value report
Buying a Salt Lake City home? Search all homes for sale


In this market, 90% of homebuyers get a loan, while 10% of buyers pay cash. If you are getting a loan, there are a few things you need to know.

It’s always crazy when we get to a closing table with a buyer who has an amazing income, great credit, and a good job only to find that they are denied from getting the loan.

The buyer then loses their earnest money and any money they spent on appraisals and inspections, not to mention the emotional investment they made in the home. If you want to get the keys to your next home, there are a few things you need to remember.

First of all, don’t make any large purchases. Don’t buy a car or any furniture. Big purchases put a balance on your credit card, which could be a red flag for lenders. Big purchases also push your ratios, which could impact your credit score. Avoid buying any big-ticket items. I would be very careful about spending over $100, and I would avoid spending over $500 altogether. You can always buy furniture once you have the keys to your home.

Also, let’s say you buy the furniture and something else happens to cause the deal to fall apart. Now, you’ve not only lost your home, but you’re also stuck with a couch you can’t return. Just wait until you actually close on the property until you buy any furniture.

“WAIT UNTIL YOU HAVE THE KEYS IN YOUR HAND BEFORE YOU MAKE ANY LARGE PURCHASES.”

Secondly, make sure you stay at your job. I’ve seen buyers quit their job just two or three days before closing. In order to buy a home, you have to have income to pay the mortgage. The bank usually verifies your employment the day of closing or the day before, so don’t quit your job the same week you close.

Even going on sabbatical or medical leave can negatively affect your closing. If you are not actively working, getting a paycheck, and making money, you won’t be able to get into that home.

Finally, don’t start applying for additional credit. If you start applying for different credit cards, your credit score will be affected. Applying for more credit also raises a red flag for the lender. They may wonder if you are applying for credit because there is an issue with your income.

Ultimately, the best thing you can do is just sit tight until you close on your home. Don’t apply for credit, don’t make any major job changes, and don’t buy a boat or a car or furniture. Just hold on until you have the keys in your hand.

Here’s a little bonus tip as well: Make sure that the down payment can be refunded. Deadlines can be moved and closing can be delayed, so make sure you are flexible with those. If the deal does fall through, make sure you can get your money back.

If you have any other questions about buying a home in our current market, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2017/September/Dont+Make+These+3+Common+Homebuyer+Mistakes+-+Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2017/September/Dont+Make+These+3+Common+Homebuyer+Mistakes+-+Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

f you are using a loan to finance your home purchase, there are three mistakes you need to avoid if you want to close on the property.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Justin Udy</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

f you are using a loan to finance your home purchase, there are three mistakes you need to avoid if you want to close on the property.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Salt Lake City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What 5 Strategies Must You Follow to Get the Home You Want?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-5-strategies-must-you-follow-to.html</link>
        
          <category>Salt Lake City Real Estate Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Justin Udy</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-12 12:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2017/September/What+5+Strategies+Must+You+Follow+to+Get+the+Home+You+Want%253F+-+Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As a buyer, there are five things you need to do to get the house you want
in our current market.


Selling your Salt Lake City home? Get a free home value report
Buying a Salt Lake City home? Search all homes for sale


At the end of June, U.S. News &amp; World Report named the greater Salt Lake area as one of the 10 best places in the nation to live in terms of home affordability, job opportunities, and the cost of living. Because we’re in a location where values continue to grow, there are five strategies you as a buyer need to follow to win in this market.

For most people, the biggest fear they have when moving on to their next home is being able to find that home in the first place. To be prepared and to combat any uncertainty, you must first get pre-approved. This will give you the ability to purchase the home you want after you sell your current home.

Second, you need to have your agent do a market analysis for you so you’re correctly evaluating the homes on the market and whether they fit your pre-approved budget.

“BE READY TO MOVE QUICKLY IF YOU SEE A HOME YOU LIKE.”

Next, you need to prep your current home for the market. The home preparation method we use for our buyers, for instance, includes our 75-point photography checklist, home staging, and our pre-inspection checklist. All this is done to make sure your home is ready to go, ready to show, and ready to sell.

After that, be knowledgeable about the market so you know how to deal with multiple offer situations. We educate all of our buyers about this subject so their offers are the ones getting accepted.

Lastly, be ready to move quickly. In our market, if you see a home you like, there are probably three or four others who like it as well. If you adhere to the four previous points mentioned above, you should be able to get the home you want.

If you have any other questions about what you need to do in order to move into your next home, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2017/September/What+5+Strategies+Must+You+Follow+to+Get+the+Home+You+Want%253F+-+Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Justin+Udy/Videos/2017/September/What+5+Strategies+Must+You+Follow+to+Get+the+Home+You+Want%253F+-+Salt+Lake+City+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

As a buyer, there are five things you need to do to get the house you want
in our current market.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Justin Udy</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

As a buyer, there are five things you need to do to get the house you want
in our current market.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Salt Lake City, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Justin Udy</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Justin Udy</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Justin Udy & Team Real Estate - your professional Salt Lake City Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
